Okay, so let's discuss the input tools and
techniques and outputs of
quality management, right?
The ITTOs of quality management.
Now, quality management has three
processes.
The very first process is this one here,
plan quality management.
And again, just as a quick review,
remember when you're looking at the
process grid, right, when you look going
down the planning column, you will see
that the very first process in planning
for each of the knowledge areas,
from scope management
all the way down, the very first
process is always plan
knowledge area management.
Right.
So in this case, the knowledge area is
quality, plan quality management.
And what artifact are we trying to create
in any of these plan management processes?
It's always the appropriate management
plan, which is documenting procedures.
Right.
So the output then, the
artifact that we're creating here
of plan quality management is
the quality management plan.
So there's our output.
And again, we have a separate video on
that, as well as the quality metric.
That's also one of the outputs,
what we are trying to create.
Now remember then, plan quality,
right?
We are trying to determine how,
right, in any of these plan management
processes and any of these management
plans, right, we are documenting how.
We are documenting procedures.
So in this case, procedures
regarding quality management,
right, what are the procedures
for testing the product?
what is the procedure for testing the
process.
Remember, quality refers to product scope
as well as project scope, right?
Making sure then you are testing the
product as well as the process,
making sure your team is doing what
they're supposed to be doing.
So we're setting the quality, pulses,
procedures for the team to follow,
making sure then that,
you know, the team will
be doing what they're
supposed to be doing.
We're going to be testing what we're
supposed to be testing.
Some of the major considerations then,
some of the inputs, right, requirements,
right, because we need to test the
product, right?
We need to know what we're supposed to be
testing.
What is what requirements has a customer
given us, right?
So we've got the requirements management
plan, risk management plan.
Risk and quality can't let go hand in
hand.
Remember, with quality,
you're trying to prevent
issues from occurring in the first place.
That's what we want to do.
A good quality management process,
right?
We'll always have procedures in place to
try and identify any potential.
failures.
If it's a potential failure, then it's a
risk.
Remember, a risk is it may or may not
happen, right?
So quality management and risk management
generally tend to go hand in hand.
If you have a good risk
management process in place,
usually you have a good quality
management process in place.
And then go to all these different tools
and techniques, again, which we will cover
in separate videos, right, at least the
important ones that you need to know.
Now, manage quality Quality refers to the
process.
So it refers to essentially
quality assurance, making sure
that a team is doing where
they're supposed to be doing.
Ensuring quality policies procedures are
being incorporated, making sure that your
team is doing where they're supposed to be
doing.
We're following procedures,
we're following standards,
following change control
procedures, for example.
We can't start an activity until we get
sign off from, say, senior management or
you know a senior stakeholder on the
project so we're making sure that we're
getting this sign off from this senior
stakeholder right so making sure
procedures are being followed plus
regulatory procedures or regulatory
standards right industry standards right
making sure all of these procedures are
being followed right ISO procedures if
you're an iso compliant organization right
are you building a house right we're
making sure then that um we're building it
according to the appropriate building
codes.
So making sure all procedures are being
followed.
So you can see then there's a lot of tools
and techniques here.
So these tools and techniques are covered
in separate videos.
One of the key artifacts
we're going to be creating, the
quality report, because one
of the tools is the audit here.
An audit is an independent review.
Again, we'll cover this in a separate
video, right, but the quality report.
The report basically then is going to be
documenting.
Are the team following procedures?
Have they been following procedures?
Along with that, testing evaluation
documents.
So we're going to be obviously doing the
testing, right?
Testing, first of all,
testing the product, which
is quality control, but
also testing the process.
So any test has to be documented.
And then the other process then is control
quality.
So the input tools and techniques and
outputs have control quality.
So remember control
quality is about testing
the product, testing
the deliverable, right?
And, you know, are we doing what we're
supposed to be doing, right?
Are we testing?
Is this testing, is the deliverable doing
what it's supposed to be doing?
Right, so we're testing the product.
Is the product doing what it's supposed to
be doing?
And basically, is it meeting requirements?
So the key output then is quality control
measurement.
which basically means documented results
of your testing, right?
Verified deliverable.
Verified deliverable basically means that,
yes, we have signed off, we've tested it,
we've signed off, and we've verified it's
doing what it's supposed to be doing.
Once we have verified
the deliverable, now we
can give it to the customer
for their acceptance.
So this actually is an input to validate
scope, which is the customer's acceptance.
So the customer can now accept the
deliverable.
But we have to test the deliverable before
the customer can accept it.
Now, verified deliverable, again,
this is covered in a separate video as
well, but verified deliverable but also
refers to not just is it meeting
requirements, is it meeting
the customers requirements,
but it's also is it
meeting standards, right?
So it's not just about making sure that
we're building the product, we have to,
you know, we We have to make sure we're
building the right product, but we also
have to make sure we're building it
correctly according to standards,
according to, say, building codes and so
and so forth.
And that's what verified deliverable
refers to, right?
And that's one of the
artifacts, one of the
outputs as well then of control quality.
Tools and techniques then, you can see
there's a big list of tools and techniques.
Again, we have separate videos and all the
important tools and techniques that we
might be utilizing to determine the
quality of our product.
Okay.
Now, one of the key inputs I want to
mention is deliverable.
Deliverable is what we are creating,
right?
Deliverable comes basically from execute
and direct to manage project work,
but the deliverable is this is what we are
testing.
We are testing the product.
I mean, you're going to be testing your
product throughout the, or testing a
deliverable throughout your
project, making sure it's, you
know, it's in line with what
we're supposed to be delivering.
So as a very simple example, you're
collecting requirements.
You're doing a quality control on those
requirements.
Are these requirements,
are we collected the
right requirements,
the right level of detail?
Do we understand what the customer wants,
what the customer needs?
If you're doing a
design, right, then you're
doing a quality control
on the design, right?
The design of this product, right,
is it a good design so that now the
developers or the, you
know, technical people can
actually build the product
based off of these design?
So you're doing a quality control
throughout your project.
Quality control is not just one testing at
the end.
It does include that as well, but all of
the different, you know, doing it
throughout the project, all of the various
deliverables throughout the project.